Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Conservation Appeals, 4
  - Subseries IV.2: Food Conservation; US Food Administration, 21
    - Victory is a / question of stamina / send the wheat / meat fats sugar / the fuel for fighters (Folder 27)
      Charging (energized) soldiers
    - Don't / stop / saving / food (Folder 27)
    - Be patriotic / Sign your country's / pledge to save the food (Folder 27)
      Lady Liberty reaching out
    - Save a loaf / a week / Help win the war (Folder 27)
      Hand cutting a loaf of bread
    - Why / Is it necessary to eat less / Meat and less wheat bread?.. .. Eat plenty, wisely, without waste, and help win the war (Folder 27)
    - Cardinal Mercier / has appealed to the / Food Administration / for more food for / starving millions / France Belgium Italy (Folder 27)
      Head of Cardinal Mercier
    - Raise more poultry / on farms and back yards / More eggs and pultry will save beef and pork (Folder 28)
      Various farm scenes related to chichen breeding and egg production
    - Help feed yourself / Make back yard and vacant lots productive / Work a garden raise chickens (Folder 28)
    - War gardens victorious / Every garden a peace plant, 1919 (Folder 28)
      Young farmer leading "troops" of vegetables carrying a US flag
    - Corn / the food of the nation / Serve some way / Every meal (Folder 28)
      Woman in kitchen with jars of cornmeal, grits, hominy, making pancakes, muffins, cereal
    - Twenty sheep to equip and / clothe each soldier / Boys and girls can help / Join a sheep club (Folder 28)
      Boys and girls on sheep farm / sheep heading down path / soldiers in rear
    - Select seed corn / Enough for two years / For 1918 plantings and to insure adapted seed for 1919, 1917-09 (Folder 28)
    - Eat more corn / the nation's most abundant cereal / Corn saved the pilgrims and fed our pioneers / corn will help us feed the world, 1017-07 (Folder 28)
      Bread, cornmeal, fish balls, lye hominy
    - Special appeal / to / Farmer patriots (from President Wilson dated April 10, 1917) / Farmers must feed the nation and its fighting men (Folder 28)
      farm scenes labeled "soldiers of the commissary"
    - Save / Seed / Corn / Now! (Folder 28)
      Uncle Sam and famer harvesting piles of corn
    - Lincoln said / Save food / for world relief (Folder 28)
      Portrait of Lincon
    - Women of Connecticut / Are you helping? / Can and dry food! (Folder 28)
      "Heroic women of France" pulling plow shares like work animals
    - The President says / Save food / Don't waste it (Folder 28)
      Portrait of Wilson
    - Hurry! / Cull your hens / Reduce feed bills / Learn How to cull / Nonlayinng hens / a poor layer / Quits early / a good layer / Lays late / Come!! To demonstration in culling non layers (Folder 28)
      2 hens
    - The Kaiser is canned / Can food / Can / Vegetables / Fruit and / the Kaiser too., 1918 (Folder 28)
      Canning jars labled tomatoes, peas, and large central jar containing the Kaiser labeled "Kaiser Brand Unsweetened"
    - Eat? / Then read this! / Your county farm bureau mans.. .. / .. .. Get behind the full pantry movement / Join your County Farm Bureau / Membership campaign March 3 to 10 (Folder 28)
    - Do not be fooled / by the lies of the / Enemy / The US Government is not taking away / from the people / .. .. Any canned goods.. .. / or used stocks of provisions bought and kept.. .. / for family use* (Folder 28)
    - Enlist today / in / the Connecticut / Canning Corps / Help connecticut meet her quota of / 5,000,000 quarts of fruit and vegetables (Folder 28)
    - America's / Food pledge / 20 million tons / Save twothirds more than last year / from stocks no larger (Folder 28)
    - Eat cane / Syrup and / Molasses / Save sugar / By using best / Louisiana molasses / and sugar cane syrup (Folder 28)
      Scales with sugar and molasses balancing each other
    - Eat more cottage cheese / You'll need / less meat (Folder 28)
      Pot of cottage cheese / photos of cow, pig, lamb, calf, hen
    - Waste no food! / Food IS wasted / Demonstrate thrift in your home! (Folder 28)
    - Will you have a part / in / victory? / "Every garden a munition plant.", 1918 (Folder 28)
      Lady Liberty sowing seeds
    - The seeds of victory / Insure the fruits of peace, 1919 (Folder 28)
      Woman farmer with assorted vegetables with faces, legs, running away
    - Wheat "I'm nearly used up with this / job of feeding the world" Corn "Why don't you call on me?", 1917 (Folder 29)
      Male figure with face of globe, dressed as Uncle sam, being fed by weeping baker as wheat supply diminishes; heap of corn and corncob figure waiting as backup
    - New York State Food Supply Commission / Headquarters / Food Consercation / "Every ounce of food you save / is ammunition to win the war" (Folder 29)
      2 US flags
    - Win the next war now / For free book on / Home canning / and / Home dryig / Write to / National War Garden Commission, 1918 (Folder 29)
      Lady Liberty canning vegetables and fruits
    - Girls / Join Uncle Sam's Commissary Army / Can and dry / Food, 1917 (?) (Folder 29)
      Woman in nurses uniform saluting; surrounded by baskets of fruits and veggies and canned products
    - Our flags / Beat Germany / Support every flag / that opposes Prussianism / Eat less of the the food fighters need / Deny yourself something / Waste nothing (Folder 29)
      Flags of the allies
    - NY State Food Supply Commission / For patriotic agriculture service / Wanted / at once men and boys.. .. / for work on farms apply to the Commissionn's County representative (Folder 29)
      Soldier in army camp; farmer in field
    - Don't let up / Keep on saving feed (Folder 29)
      Soldier looming over sinking figure of Hun
    - Patriotic food exhibit / at / the Mark Twain Library / Reading / Wednesday, Apr 24 / at 2 o'clock (Folder 29)
    - Kill the slacker / Spare the good birds / Old hen week / Beginning August 27, 1917 (?) (Folder 29)
      Man chasing chicken with an axe; woman feeding hens
    - New England peaches / Now at their best / Provide a supply for winter use (Folder 29)
      Boy and girl eating peaches
    - Stop, Look and Listen, 1917 (?) (Folder 29)
      Railroad crossing post
    - Sugar means ships / The consumption of / Sugar sweetened drinks / Must be reduced (Folder 29)
      Girl sipping drink; war in Europe rages; boats carrying soldiers to front; ships with sugar returning
    - Food don't waste it / 1. Use less wheat and meat / 2. Buy local foods / 3. Serve just enough / 4. Use what's left (Folder 29)
    - Our problem is to feed our allies theis winter .. .. / Our solution is to eat less of .. .. / foods of which we have an abundance, and to waste / Less of all foods (Folder 29)
    - The gospel / Of the / Clean plate / Don't waste any food (Folder 29)
      Clean plate
    - Get behind our soldiers / Sailors / and our Allies. Send them the most food possible in the least shipping / Space, 1917 (Folder 29)
      Ships at sea
    - Save a loaf a week / Help win the war (Folder 29)
      Knife slicing loaf of bread
    - Help your boy / at the front / Use less wheat and / Meat / Send more to him (Folder 29)
      Soldier, flag at front
    - Eat more / Cornmeal rye flour / Oatmeal / and barley / save the wheat / for the fighters, 1918 (?) (Folder 29)
      Cannisters of cornmeal, rye flour, oatmeal, barley; mounted soldiers (rear)
    - Engineer / if you are a patriot / if this is your fight / Get into it / Stop the ammonia leaks, 1918 (Folder 29)
      Uncle Sam holding wrench, encouraging worker to get up from chair
    - Food conservation week, December 1 to 7, 1918/ We now appeal to your sympathy for world relief / Read the Hoover message (Folder 29)
    - Little / Americans / Do your bit / Leave nothig on your plate (Folder 29)
      Baby saluting a bowl of oatmeal
  - Subseries IV.3: Daylight Savings, 22
    - Saving daylight / "Set the clock ahead one hour and win the war!" / ave 1,000,000 / Tons of coal by / Using an extra / Hour of daylight! (Folder 30)
      Uncle Sam shoveling coal; small soldier with face of clock set to daylight savings time
    - "Saving daylight!" / Gain an hour / of daylight / "Just set the clock ahead one hour, / Uncle no longer working day for / Anybody but all of it in daylight. / Use the extra hour of daylight for your country" (Folder 30)
      Uncle Sam turning the clock ahead (on body of soldier)
    - Saving Daylight! / "Set the clock ahead / One hour and / Win the war!" / Uncle Sam, your enemies hav been up and are at / Work on the extra hour of daylight when will you wake up? (Folder 30)
      Uncle Sam waking up at 8 AM; in background German and Austrian soldiers already at work; small figure withface of clock pointing to them
    - "Saving daylight" / Let your congressman know you / Favor the law to start eight / Hour day's work at 7 o'clock AM / and end it at 4 o'clock PM (Folder 30)
    - Saving Daylight / "Set the clock ahead / one hour and / wint he war!" / Mobilize an extra / Hour of daylight and / Help win the war (Folder 30)
      Uncle Sam holding hoe and rifle marching behind small soldier with face of Day Light Savings Clock
  - Subseries IV.4: US Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation, 23
    - The tidal wave / July 4, 1918 / 95 ships launched (Folder 31)
      Fleet of ships and tidal wave of infantry soldiers on horesback; planes
    - Mechanincs wanted to / Volunteer as needed for / Government ship building / "Ships, ships / and / More ships!" / "Ships will win the war!" / Descriptive circular in side (Folder 31)
      Uncle Sam behinnd shipbulder and a fleet of ships
    - Man those ships! / Enroll here for / the Merchant Marines (Folder 31)
      Eagle soaring above US ships sailing out of harbor
    - Our country needs ships / Be true to the boys who are / Giving their lives for you (Folder 31)
      Shipbuilding scene
    - To everyone / in this plant .. .. / Our country is depending on you (Folder 31)
    - The ships are coming / On the job for victory (Folder 31)
    - On the job for victory (Folder 31)
      Rivetter in shipyard
    - Are you working / With Schwab? / Charles M. Schwab / Director General of the Emergency Fleet Corporation / Says / "I want all the men in the shipyards / to feel that they are workig with me, not for me" (Folder 31)
      CS at shipyard with workmen
    - Make every minute count for Pershing (Folder 31)
      Shipbuilder putting on rivets
- Series V: Relief Appeals, 5
  Series V: Relief Appeals, includes posters requesting aid for foreign countries, children, soldiers and their families, and animals. United War Work Campaign materials are included.
  - Subseries V.1: Relief for Foreign Countries, 24
    - Build the Jewish Homeland now / Palestine Reconstruction Fund $3,000,000 (Folder 32)
      scene in Palestine
    - 2 Million / Starving / Armenian Syrian Women Children / 17 cents a day will / Save a life!, 1918 (?) (Folder 32)
    - Your intelligence is your / Biggest asset / Enlist / A call / Recruiting station / the college Christian Association, President's office / for Armenian and Syrian Relief Committee, 1 Madison Ave, NY, 1917 (?) (Folder 32)
    - Starving / Help now, 1917 (?) (Folder 32)
      distraught woman over dead baby
    - The fatherless / Children of France, 1917 (?) (Folder 32)
      Lady liberty offering aid to war-torn children and adults
    - Italy / Defending / Freedom / and Art / Send your check to the / Italian War Relief Fund / of America 347 Madison Ave. NY / Room 2011 (Folder 32)
      Italian soldier before landscape with Roman ruins
    - Printed message of handwriting "Your little friend in Bible Lands / Shushan" (Folder 32)
      Head of child
    - "You won't let me starve will you?" / The opportunity for your Sunday School / 17 cents a day $5.00 a month $60.00 a year will save a life! (Folder 32)
      Tinted photo of child named Shushan
    - You saved them in 1917 / Will you let them starve now? / Here is the beginning of American Jewry's 1918 answer (Folder 32)
      two helpless children / bombed out village near
    - (?) Message in Hebrew (Folder 32)
      Scene of Palestine (same as poster: "Build the Jewish Homeland Now")
    - Lest they perish (Folder 32)
      Middle Eastern woman with baby tied to back
    - Wanted / 2,000,000 / Garments / For Destitute men, women, and children in / Occupied northern / France and Belgium / Under Auspices or American Red Cross (Folder 32)
    - "The Child at your door" / 400,000 Orphans starving / Campaign for $30,000,000 (Folder 32)
      portrait of Near Eastern Child
    - The children of Syria / "Christmas Land" / Appeal for aid to / Presbyterian Sunday Schools (Folder 33)
      photo of Syrian children; drawing of man on camel in desert
    - Don't let them die / You can save them / send contributions to the / Women's Apparel Association / 132 West 42nd Street / New York City / J. Wise, Treasurer, 1918 (Folder 33)
      Old woman with child in one arm, dead child on lap
    - Help us to help them / American Women's Hospitals / Campaigh for Serbia / and the Near East (Folder 33)
      A.W.H. soldier ministering a child with baby in arms
    - Play the game / It is our duty to respect the / Property of our allies.. .. / Remember! / They have not only lost all / Their possessions but have also / Suffered untold misery (Folder 33)
    - Help a Greek child / to survive / Contribute to Friends of Greece, INC, 52 East 57th St, NYC (Folder 33)
      A bleary -eyed Greek child
    - President Wilson speaks / for America: / "I welcome and opportunity / to express the satisfaction / I have felt in / the progress / of the Zionist / Movement in the United States" (Folder 33)
      profile figure of Wilson
    - British American War Relief / Headquarters / 5 East 59th St. (pasted on) / New York (Folder 33)
      Lady Liberty knitting (copyright LC Whitridge)
    - Where the victims are / Save the survivors (Folder 33)
      Map of Near East with statistics of no. of square miles; no. of non-Moslems in area; no. of dead
    - For the boys and girls of Syria and Persia / A Christmas offering / From our Sunday schools (Folder 33)
      map of Near East; 2 red arrows; our Syria Mission (pointing to Jerusalem); our Persia mission (pointing to Teheran)
    - Lest we perish / Campaign for $30,000,000 / American Committee / For Relief in the Near East (Folder 33)
      Middle Eastern girl asking for aid
    - Keep me alive / 400,000 / Children starving / in Bible Lands (Folder 33)
      tinted photo of child
    - Give or we perish / American Committee / for Relief in the Near East / Armenia Greece Syria Persia (Folder 33)
      Near Eastern woman's torso
    - Erin's appeal to America / "Help my Irish / Disabled" (Folder 33)
      Wounded soldier with girl's arm around him asking for helf from Statue of Liberty / NY skyline rear
    - American Women's Hospitals / Help women physicians / Fight disease and death / In Serbia and the Near East (Folder 33)
      Female MD strangling snake to protect child; dying people in rear
    - Tired of giving? / You don't know what it is to be tired (Folder 33)
      woman and child on bombed out rubble (also: "Courtesy of NY Tribune")
    - Polish Day / At hero land / December 4th, 1917 / Polish Christmas Festival in the afternoon / Pagent of Poland in the evening (Folder 33)
      war scene: woman with dead daughter (or sleeping) and boy (possibly weeping) in lap
  - Subseries V.2: Relief for Soldiers, Sailors, and their Families, 25
    - New York Catholic / and Knights of Columbus / War Camp Fund / to help the government with the war (Folder 34)
      Soldiers before K of C barracks with sign "everybody welcome"
    - Proclamation / Ball and Bat fund / Now / For a / "Sacrifice" / for the / boys in the / trenches (Folder 34)
      Uncle Sam at bat
    - War Infromation / No Charge (Folder 34)
      Uncle Sam in uniform, holding pencil, "ready to give advice"
    - Knowledge wins / Public Library / Books / Are / Free (Folder 34)
      soldier with pile of books on varying subjects; Manhattan skyline in rear
    - A million dollars / for / a million books / for / a million soldiers / Camp Library Week / Sept 24 30 (Folder 34)
    - A necessary part / of your equipment / at you camp library (Folder 34)
    - Get "Smileage Books" / Inside (Folder 34)
    - Buy "Smileage Books" / Now / they mean / happy offduty hours for / those who fight for us (Folder 34)
    - What are you doing for / our boys over there / "We must fire all / we can to Northampton's / War Chest Fund", 1918 (Folder 34)
      2 soldiers, 2 sailors, nurse with war chest filled with coins
    - Why not advance / Books will help especially those about / the war and the training necessary to win it (Folder 34)
    - They signal / "Send Books" (Folder 34)
      soldiers / sailors and semaphore flags
    - Empty! Sammy's "SOS" / "Send Over Smokes". / Our Boys in France Tobacco Fund, 25 West 44th Street, NYC (Folder 34)
      soldier with empty cigarette tin
    - Cover design of the book of the hour / The Defender of Democracy / To be sold by the Militia of Mercy for the benefit / of the needy families of our soldiers of the sea (Folder 34)
      soldier, sailor (both wounded) sharing sword; nurse looking after them; heraldic fondo frame
    - American / Godmothers League / for the American Soldiers / in France (Folder 34)
      a Godmother carrying Red Cross packages; soldiers sitting on hillock near ocean
    - Philadelphia's sons by the thousands / are going "over there" / to be united sing / "Music and entertainment are as essential to the soldier / as food and sleep" Pershing, 1918-05-02 (Folder 34)
    - Books / for our / soldiers and sailors / leave them here (Folder 34)
    - Give to the / American / Chocolate / Fund for / US Soldiers / in France (Folder 34)
      Tubby soldier smiling and patting his tummy
    - Books for our soldiers and sailors / a million needed at once (Folder 34)
      American eagle holding a book
    - Books / for our / soldiers and sailors / Leave them here / or take them to / the Public Library (Folder 34)
    - ABFB / Permanent Blind Relief War Fund / 590 Fifth Ave (Folder 34)
      Blind soldier
    - While he is doing this for us / we must do this for him / that's why / New York Infirmary / for Women and Children needs / $200,000. / 321 E. 15th St / NYC / Campaign Headquarters, Hotel McAlpin (Folder 34)
      1. Soldier in battle; 2. Nurses tending sick babies and woman in infirmary
    - Send Sammy Smileage / $1.00 / Let your soldier see camp shows as your guest / Send him "Smileage" (Folder 34)
    - The Militia of Mercy / 4 West 49th St, NYC / Authorized by / the Hon. Josepitus Daniels, Secty of the Navy / and by / Commodore RP Forshew / Commanding the Naval Militia of State of NY / to care for the families of the Naval Militiamen (Folder 34)
      Naval militiaman with wife and 2 kids
    - Smileage Books / are passes to camp theatres / Buy one here (Folder 34)
      Soldier pointing to crowd; soldiers awaiting entry to Liberty Theatre; hand removing $5.00 Smileage cupon book from enevelope
    - This is "Soldier's Smoke Week!" / Send a kit of cheer to a lonely / American soldier in France! / Address your contributions to / "Our Boys in France Tobacco Fund" (Folder 34)
      Soldier smoking cheroot (?) cigar; etherial image of female behind him
    - Hold on to / Uncle Sam's Insurance / the strongest, safest and cheapest insurance in the world / Keep it up after you are back in civil life (Folder 34)
      soldiers, sailor holding US Treasury Dept Certificate of War Risk Insurance
    - Now for / some / music / Draft your / Slacker Records / They will go to camp / or overseas through / the National Phonograph Records Recruiting Corps. (Folder 34)
      soldiers smiling over large record and phono player
    - American British French Belgian / Permanent Blind Relief War Fund / for soldiers and sailors / American Saction under the patronage of / Pres. Woodrow Wilson / Headquarters, 590 Fifth Ave, NYC (Folder 34)
      nurse guiding blind soldier
  - Subseries V.3: Children's Relief, 26
    - The health of the child / Is the power of the nation / April 1918 / Children's Year / April 1919 / for every soldier lost over there, save a baby over here (Folder 35)
      Band of healthy children on country hill
    - Know Where Your Community Fails / Bad Housing / Crowded Schools / Bad Working Conditions, 1919 (Folder 35)
      1. Tenaments, 2. Crowded classroom, 3. Factory setting
    - Know What Your / Community Does / For Babies / For Young Folks / For Everyone, 1919 (Folder 35)
      1. Baby health care centre, 2. The city playground, 3. The community centre
    - Home is the First / School of Citizenship, 1919 (Folder 35)
      woman and child laundering clothes
    - Good Citizens at School, 1919 (Folder 35)
      chldren in classroom
    - The Good Citizen Plays Fair, 1919 (Folder 35)
      children playing basketball
    - The good citizen / Does not / Play ball in the street / Uncover sewers.. .. / Break glass.. .. / Use a BeanShooter / Tease Animals, 1919 (Folder 35)
      kids on street doing these no-nos
    - "In God We Trust" / Washiongton at Valley Forge, 1919 (Folder 35)
      GW praying in forest (from the Bronze on the Sub-Treasury, NY)
    - We Cannot have privileges / without responsibilites, 1919 (Folder 35)
      scales of justice; Rights and Privelidges balancing Duties and Responsabilities
    - School Gardens / Turn / Spare Time / Idle Land / Surplus Energy / into / Good Times / Good Things to Eat / Good Health, 1919 (Folder 35)
      school garden with children working in it
    - This is hard on the motorman / It may prove hard on you, 1919 (Folder 35)
      2 children dodging trolley; hitching aride at rear of trolley
    - Back to school / drive / Children back in schol / means / soldiers back in jobs / Children's Year / April 6, 1918 / April 6, 1919, 1919 - 1918 (Folder 35)
    - The Children's Year / April 6, 1918 to April 6, 1919 / Fathers and Mothers of America! Uncle Sam asks, Are your children / up to standard in their / height and weight?, 1919 - 1918 (Folder 35)
      baby on scale; boy being measured for height
    - Avoid danger / Look both ways / .. .. Cross only at the crossing, 1919 (Folder 35)
      child on curb preparing to cross street
    - Protect Public Property, 1919 (Folder 35)
      schoolboy carving initial on desk
    - Save Money to / Help Yourself and Others / Save for Worthwhile Things / Such As / Travel, Education, Tools, a Bicycle, a Watch, 1919 (Folder 35)
      boy buing tickets for bat trip for himself and a friend on crutches (trip up Hudson to West Point, Newburg, Pughekeepsie, or Albany)
    - Make Your Quarter / Buy a Quarter's Worth, 1919 (Folder 35)
      "boy" with head of quarter buying merchandise
    - "Waste is Worse than Loss" / Thomas A. Edison, 1919 (Folder 35)
      woman in kitchen; all three burners aflame on stove; water pouring from sink spigot; 1/2 loaf of bread dumped into garbage
    - Your City is Your City / Keep it Clean / Find the Good Citizen, 1919 (Folder 35)
      man spitting; man tossing paper; boy dumping orange peels; boy throwing bananna peel into garbage bin
    - Cleanliness / "Begins At Home", 1919 (Folder 35)
      boy swatting flies; girl washing dishes
    - Everyone respects a tidy / Girl and boy, 1919 (Folder 35)
      boy shining boots; girl whisking curtains
    - Your Body / Is Your Mind's House. / Keep it Clean, 1919 (Folder 35)
      boy washing at sink
    - Do You Know / What Place This Is? / Who Works Here? / What is Done Here?, 1919 (Folder 35)
      US Capitol Building
    - Children's / Year / Send aid / to the Mayor's Committee of Women on National Defense, 1919 - 1918 (Folder 35)